Itachi's Story –
Light and Darkness: Truth
DUMPLINGS
(サスケ)カカシ アンタが
先にいるなんて珍しいな。
Kakashi.
It's unusual that
you're here first.
(カカシ)まぁ たまにはな。
Well, it happens once in a while.
こんな所に呼び出して 何の用だ？
What's going on?
Why did you summon us here?
《イタチ : サスケ。
Sasuke!
大きくなったな》
You've grown up…
(イタチ)久しぶりだな サスケ。
It's been a long time, Sasuke.
うちはイタチ…。
Itachi Uchiha!
アンタを… 殺す！
I will…
…kill you!
(鬼鮫)ほう 写輪眼。
しかも あなたによく似て。
Ah…the Sharingan.
I see a resemblance…
Just who is he?
いったい 何者です？
俺の弟だ。
He's my younger brother.
《写輪眼は 開いたか。
そうでなくてはな》
So you've awakened your Sharingan.
Otherwise…
アンタの言ったとおり
アンタを恨み 憎み→
It's just as you've said.
I've hated you, and resented you.
そして アンタを
殺すためだけに俺は！
I have lived my life…
《どれだけ強くなった？》
How strong have you gotten?
俺は… 生きてきた！
…for the sole purpose
of killing you…
《千鳥》
Chidori?!
うお～っ！
《そうか カカシさんが…》
I see…it was Kakashi, huh?
うわ～っ！
(ナルト)サスケ！ チクショウ…。
Sasuke!
Damn it!
忍法 口寄せの…。
遅い。
Ninja Art: Summoning—!
Too slow!
(イタチ)自来也様。
Master Jiraiya!
(自来也)目当ては やはりナルトか。
So your target is Naruto,
after all?
ナルト君を連れて行くのが
暁から下された→
Taking Naruto is the overriding
mission we have been assigned to,
我々への至上命令。
by the Akatsuki.
ナルトは やれんのう。
I can't let you have Naruto.
どうですかね？
I wonder about that…
ちょうどいい お前ら２人は
ここで わしが始末する。
Perfect timing. I will get rid of
both of you right here.
手出すな…。
Don't interfere…
コイツを殺すのは…。
If anyone is going to kill him…
It will be me.
俺だ。
今 お前などに興味はない。
I have no interest
in you right now.
《今は まだだ サスケ》
Not yet, Sasuke.
うっ うわっ！
サスケ！ チクショウが！
Sasuke!
Damn it!
ナルト！
手出すなっつってんだろうが！
Naruto!
I said not to interfere!
これは 俺の戦いだ…。
This is my fight!
《そうだ》
That's right.
上等だ!!
Fine by me!
ぐっ…。
《イタチ : まだ足りないんだ》
You still don't have enough…
《イタチ : 許せ サスケ。
Forgive me, Sasuke.
許せ…》
Forgive me!
容赦ないですね。
You are merciless.
《憎め この俺を》
Hate me…
(イタチ)お前は弱い。
You are weak.
今から24時間 あの日をさまよえ。
From now, for 24 hours…
Relive that day.
うわ～っ!!
弟相手に月読ですか？
Using Tsukuyomi on
your younger brother?
いいかげんに… しやがれ!!
That's enough…outta…you!
うっ… あっ…。
なぜ 弱いか。
You are weak, because
you don't have enough hatred.
足りないからだ。 憎しみが。
鬼鮫 来い。
チッ。
C'mon, Kisame!
待て！
Wait! Why you—!
なぜ 退く必要が？ あなたなら…。
Why did we have to retreat?
You could have—!
《サスケ 三代目が死んでも まだ→
Sasuke…
Even though Lord Third is dead,
お前を守る者たちがいるんだな。
you still have people
who will protect you…
待っているぞ サスケ》
I'll be waiting, Sasuke.
なぜ そこまで弟にこだわる？
アイツは 抜け忍だろう。
Why are you so obsessed
with my brother?
He's just a Rogue Ninja.
少なくとも お前なんかより→
That's because, unlike you…
アイツのことを
兄弟だと思っているからだ。
He's more of a brother to me
than you are to him…
お前は サスケを
連れ戻したがっていたな？
You've been trying to take Sasuke
back to the village.
だが うまくいかなかったら
どうする？
But what if it doesn't
go the way you want it to?
どうやってでも連れ戻す。
I'll do anything to bring him back!
さっき お前は
サスケを兄弟のようだと言ったな。
You just said you consider
Sasuke to be like a brother…
ならば もし そのサスケが→
What if Sasuke were to attack
the Hidden Leaf Village?
木ノ葉を襲ってきたら
どうすると聞いているんだ。
What would you do then?
なんだ？ なんで サスケが…
そんなこと するわけねえだろ！
What? Why would Sasuke—?
There's no way
he'd do something like that!
サスケは まだ純粋だ。
Sasuke is still a blank canvas.
簡単に何色にでも染まる。
He can easily be dyed
into any color.
そうなった場合
お前は ヤツを止められるのか？
In that case,
would you be able to stop him?
サスケを殺してでも。
Even if you have to kill Sasuke?
Could you weigh Sasuke against
the Hidden Leaf on a set of scales?
サスケと木ノ葉を
天秤にかけられるのか？
くっ！ 木ノ葉は守る！
I would defend the Leaf Village!
そんでもってサスケも殺さず止める！
And I would find a way to stop
Sasuke without killing him!
子供だな。
お前の話は 絵空事ばかりだ。
You're such a child…
What you speak of
are all fantasies.
忍はときに厳しい選択を
迫られることだってある。
A shinobi must be capable of
making very harsh decisions.
前にも一度 同じことを言われた。
Someone else tried to tell me
the same thing before.
でも選択肢なんてねえ。
But for me, there is no choice.
I never go back on my word…
まっすぐ自分の言葉は曲げねえ。
それが俺の忍道だ！
That's my Ninja Way.
《そうか》
I see.
来たか。
You've come…
その写輪眼
お前は どこまで見えている？
That Sharingan…
How much can you actually see?
今の俺の
この眼に見えているのは→
What I'm seeing right now…
イタチ アンタの死に様だ。
Is your death, Itachi.
俺の死に様か。
My death, huh?
では…。
Well then…
…make it happen.
再現してみろ。
うっ… う…。
許せ サスケ。 これで最後だ。
Forgive me, Sasuke…
This is the end.
俺のことをずっと許さなくていい。
You don't ever have to forgive me.
俺は お前をずっと愛している。
I will love you always.
《俺は…》
I…
《決めたよ 兄さん》
I've made up my mind, Big Brother…
(マダラ)あとは ヤツらか。
All that's left…is them.
(ゼツ)やはり 光を通さなかったか。
So it really didn't
let the light through…
やっとだ。
Finally…
どうやら あの黒い野郎は
平気みてぇだな。
Looks like it didn't affect
that black one.
サスケ みんなを
幻術から覚まさせるには→
Sasuke!
What do we do to release everyone
from the genjutsu?!
どうすりゃいい？
輪廻眼の幻術は
輪廻眼で処理できる おそらくな。
Rinnegan genjutsu can be dealt with
using Rinnegan, probably.
(カカシ)サスケの左目が
必要ということか。
Which means we need
Sasuke's left eye.
そうはさせない。
I won't let that happen.
あとは
お前たちを処理するだけだ。
All that's left to do is to
get rid of you guys…
(マダラ)世界の救世主たる俺がな。
Which I, the savior
of the world will do.
マダラ！
Madara!
That eye on his forehead!
(サクラ)あの額の目。
気をつけろ。 ヤツの影４体に
四方を囲まれてるぞ。
Be careful.
We're surrounded in all directions
by four of his Shadows.
わかってんよ。
I know that!
I won't allow you to
do anything further.
もうお前らには何もさせん。
I just severed the Karmic Cycle
of this world.
今 この世の因果を
断ち切ったのだ。
I have freed humankind
人々から苦しみ 痛み
むなしさを切り離したのだ。
from their suffering,
pain and their futility.
But all this…is just a lie!
こんなの ウソっぱちじゃねえか！
ナルト。 皆の幸せの
邪魔をしているのだ お前は。
Naruto, you're the one
who's interfering
with everyone's happiness.
見ろ。 すべての忍が
戦いをやめた世界を。
Just look at this world now.
All fighting between shinobi
has ceased.
I've transformed hell into heaven.
俺は 地獄を天国へと変えた。
柱間の間違いを
ようやく正したのだ。
I've finally corrected
Hashirama's mistake.
初代火影様の間違いって
なんのことよ？
What do you mean by
the First Hokage's "mistake"?
お前たち木ノ葉の者は
認めたくないだろうが→
You Hidden Leaf may not
want to acknowledge it,
but Hashirama ultimately failed
in reforming the Shinobi World.
結局 柱間は失敗したのだ。
忍世界の変革に。
最初は 柱間も俺も
目的は一緒だった。
In the beginning, both Hashirama
and I had the same goals.
そして 一緒に行動を始めた。
And we worked together.
(マダラ)年端もいかぬ子供ですら
戦いに駆り出される→
We tried to change
the shinobi world
that sent out barely grown
children out to war.
忍の世界を変えようとした。
(マダラ)２人で忍の里を作った。
The two of us created
the shinobi village.
だが それでは
真の平和には たどり着けない。
However, that does not result
in true peace.
人は 腹の奥 はらわたまで
見せ合うことはできない。
People cannot show
each other their true feelings.
恐れ 疑い 憎むことは
決して止まない。
Fear, suspicion, and resentment…
…never subside.
俺の主張は退けられた。
FIRE
LIGHTNING WIND
EARTH WATER
FIRE
LIGHTNING WIND
EARTH WATER
My opinions were pushed aside
FIRE
LIGHTNING WIND
EARTH WATER
and the Shinobi World moved forward
忍の世界は 柱間の
理想のもとに進んでいった。
and the Shinobi World moved forward
in accordance with
Hashirama's vision.
だが それで どうなった？
And what happened because of it?
The fighting between shinobi
hasn't stopped.
忍同士の戦いは止まらぬ。
止まらぬどころか
里を作ったことによって→
Rather than ceasing,
establishing ninja villages led to
軍事力は高まり→
an increase in
their military build-up,
which resulted in battles
that turned into great wars…
戦いは 大戦と呼ばれる
規模に膨れ上がり→
死傷者の数は 膨大となった。
with countless lives lost.
第一次 忍界大戦。
The battling in what became
the First Great Ninja War…
第二次 忍界大戦。
The Second Great Ninja War…
第三次 忍界大戦。
The Third Great Ninja War…
戦いは止まぬ。
それが 柱間の作った忍世界だ。
The fighting never stopped.
That is Hashirama's legacy
to the Shinobi World.
もっとも この第四次 忍界大戦は
俺が仕掛けたものだがな。
Although I admit that I triggered
this Fourth Great Ninja War…
(サクラ)そうよ。
あなたのせいで大勢が死んだ！
That's right! Because of you,
so many people died!
おとなしく尾獣を渡せという
提案はしたはずだ。
I did make a proposition
to peacefully hand over
the Tailed Beasts.
今 人は皆 神樹の中で→
Right now, everyone is
inside the Divine Tree.
Each one of them,
dreaming their own idyllic dreams.
それぞれが幸せな夢を見ている。
自分の理想の世界の中にいるのだ。
They are in their own ideal worlds.
これが お前の理想の世界か。
Is this your idea of
a perfect world?
人に ただ
まやかしを与えただけだろ！
You're just deceiving people.
俺は 忍の長き戦いの歴史から→
I just want to be the savior
that ends the long history of
fighting amongst shinobi.
救世主として
争いを取り除いたのだ。
もう 理解しろ。
すべて終わったのだ。
Just know this…
It's all over.
(ゼツ)違う マダラ。
You're wrong, Madara.
お前は 救世主でもなく
そして終わりでもない。
You are not the savior…
Nor is this the end of things…
《動けん…》
I can't…move…
(サクラ)何なの？
What's going on?
なぜ お前が オビトとは違い→
How can you say that you,
unlike Obito,
すべてを利用する側だと
言い切れる？
are able to completely
take advantage of others?
自分だけが違うと思うのは
おこがましくないか？
Isn't that presumptuous to think
that you alone are different?
マダラよ お前もまた
幻の夢の中にいたのだ。
My dear Madara…
You have also been inside
a phantom dream…
俺の描いた夢の中に。
Inside a dream that I concocted.
黒ゼツ お前は何を言っている？
Black Zetsu…
What are you saying?
お前を作ったのは俺だ。
I created you.
お前は 俺の
意志そのものなんだぞ。
You are my will incarnate!
そこも違う。
Wrong again…
俺の意志は カグヤだ。
My will is…
Kaguya's!
どうなってんだってばよ。
What the hell is going on?
ここへきて仲間割れか？
They're having a falling out,
at this stage in the game?
いや そうじゃない。
No, that's not it.
He just mentioned Kaguya.
アイツ今 カグヤと言った。
カグヤ？
何それ？
Huh? Kaguya?
What is that?
六道仙人が言っていたヤツだ。
The one the Sage of
the Six Paths mentioned.
((今のマダラが まさにそれだ。
The current Madara is
a prime example of that…
まるで母 カグヤのようだ。
He's become just like
my mother, Kaguya.
十尾の力を得て わしに近づき→
He's obtained Ten Tails' power
and is getting close to me…
母 カグヤの力にさえ
近づこうとしている。
and is trying to attain even
my mother Kaguya's power.
やがて母の力は うぬぼれを生み→
In time, my mother's power
eventually gave rise to hubris…
(人々は その力の存在を
恐れるようになっていった))
And the populace came to fear
the existence of that power.
まさか…。
No way…
(扉間)何だ？
What is it?!
チャクラを吸い取っているのか。
Is their chakra being absorbed?
ぐぉ～っ！
What's up with this guy?
何だってばよ コイツ。
すげぇチャクラだ。
This chakra is ridiculous!
あたりのマダラの影が すべて消えた。
All of Madara's shadows that were
surrounding us have disappeared!
何かあるぞ！
Something's about to happen!
It's chakra!
チャクラだ！
うわっ！
ハハハッ！
地中から噴き出たチャクラを
どんどん吸収してるのか!?
Is he absorbing all the chakra
that's erupting from the ground?
どこから こんな
濃い いっぱいのチャクラが!?
Where is all this thick potent
chakra coming from?
無限月読に
捕まってるヤツらのものだろう。
It's probably from everyone trapped
in the Infinite Tsukuyomi!
ギャーッ！
このままじゃヤベエぞ サスケ！
This is really bad, Sasuke!
これ十尾どころじゃねえぞ チャクラ！
This chakra is much stronger
than Ten Tails'!
動く前に止める！
Stop them before they move!
いけ ナルト！
Go, Naruto!
コイツが膨れてるうちに
止めるってこったな。
You mean while they're
still swelling up, right?
火に飛び入る虫２匹。
Like two moths flying
into the flame…
お前らも今 この場で
チャクラを吸収してやる。
I'm going to absorb all the chakra
out of the two of you right now.
クソッ…。
Damn it!
待て サクラ！
でも…。
Don't, Sakura!
But!
考えなしなら 無意味になる。
Action without a plan
is meaningless.
チクショウ！
Damn it!
《動けねえ…》
I can't move!
Sasuke! If we don't stop him now…
サスケ コイツを倒して止めねえと→
俺らより先に
みんなのチャクラが吸収されて→
He'll drain everyone else's chakra
before ours and they'll all die!
死んじまうぞ！
くっ…。
安心しろ 皆を殺したりはしない。
Don't worry,
no one is going to die.
かつて カグヤは この無限月読を
人々にかけたが→
Even when Kaguya previously cast
the Infinite Tsukuyomi
upon the populace,
殺さずに生かしたまま
保存しておいた。
she kept them alive and preserved…
カグヤの兵として生産するために。
…in order to form them
into her soldiers.
生産？ どういうことだ。
"Form"? What do you mean?!
フッ イタチよりは鈍いようだな。
You seem to be denser than Itachi.
How can one use
ordinary people in combat?
ただの人間が戦闘で使えるか。
うっ…。
まさか…。
You're not saying that—!
She converted them
into White Zetsu.
(ゼツ)白ゼツにするのだ。
かつての無限月読にかかった
者どもの成れの果ての姿。
What's left of those who were under
the previous Infinite Tsukuyomi…
それが白ゼツだ。
That's what White Zetsu are.
ゆっくりと時間をかけて
変化させる。
They've been transformed
ever so slowly over time.
なら みんなあの白いのに
なっちまうってことか？
Are you saying everyone's gonna
turn into those white things?!
黒ゼツ 何を言っている。
What are you saying, Black Zetsu?
The Infinite Tsukuyomi
is an Uchiha Jutsu!
無限月読は うちはによって
忍世界に→
One that brings eternal peace
to the shinobi world.
永遠の平和をもたらす術だ。
(ゼツ)お前のその根拠はなんだ？
And what do you base that on?
六道仙人が…。
The Sage of the Six Paths…
carved that into the stone tablet.
石碑にそう書き記した。
書いてあった！
(ゼツ)マダラよ。
My dear Madara…
I have been around
for eons longer than you.
俺は お前などより
はるか昔から存在している。
Since finding the stone tablet
left by Hagoromo,
ハゴロモの残した石碑を見つけ
修正する時間は十分にあった。
I've had quite some time
to make revisions.
修正だと？
Did you say "revisions"?
The Infinite Tsukuyomi
is not a jutsu
(ゼツ)無限月読は
平和の夢を与える術ではない。
that confers peaceful dreams.
It is a jutsu to amass
enormous amounts of chakra
個々の持つチャクラを集め
膨大な量に高める術だ。
from individuals enslaved in it.
なんのために…。
For what purpose?
(ゼツ)お前はそのために
動いていたのだ。
You acted merely for that purpose.
俺の… いや カグヤの意志によって。
According to
俺が そんな…。
(ゼツ)お前がオビトを
駒として使ったように→
お前も また１つの駒だったのだ。
あっ！
おい すっげえ 膨れてんぞ！
吸収しすぎたチャクラに耐えられず
膨張しているんだ！
このままじゃ 砕け散る！
なぜだ なぜこんな…。
《柱間…
俺はどこで間違えたんだ？》
縮んでる。
オビト！
コイツ…
コイツ大じいちゃんが言ってた…。
大筒木カグヤ！